本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
圣  城  风  云
『第一季  第四集』
翻译  Ijoy
翻译  小易
翻译  ala365
翻译  小熊嘟嘟
翻译  苏小黛
时间轴  veryink
校对  苏小黛
后期  渔夫
特效  WiLL
总监制  苏小黛
布拉提斯
Brastias!
Brastias!!
亚瑟
Arthur.
传我旨意  叫所有战士起床
I want every warrior out of his bed.
命高文开始训练他们
Tell Gawain he starts training everyone.
即刻就去
Right away.
遵命
Of course.
早上好  夫人
Good morning... wife.
早上好  夫君
Morning, husband.
-你在偷看我的睡相吗  -是
- Were you watching me sleep? - Yes.
-你真是少见多怪  -我很幸运
- You are so strange. - I'm lucky.
我是唯一能窥见你这副模样的人
I'm the only man who ever gets to see you like this.
你是个好人
You're a good man.
那么
So...
我们何时能离开卡米洛特
So when can we leave Camelot?
恐怕没那么简单
I don't think it's going to be that simple.
里昂提斯
Leontes,
你答应过我婚礼之后就去请示国王
you promised after the wedding you would talk to the king
封我们一些土地  让我们生活在一起
about getting some land and a place for us to live together.
是  我知道  但是
Yes, I know, but...
里昂提斯  别枕边厮磨啦
Leontes, put her down!
国王要召集所有战士
The king wants all his warriors now!
我明白
I understand.
我们迟早会离开的
And in time we will.
但现在国王需要他的护卫
But right now the king needs his champion...
伴其左右
here.
你能理解的  对吗
You understand that, don't you?
早餐
Breakfast.
为何不下楼跟他一起用餐
Why don't you go down, eat with him?
我在等他邀请我
I'm waiting to be invited.
也许有必要小小的引导一下
Perhaps a little guidance is needed.
你可否传书到卡米洛特说我们要去
Did you send word to Camelot to expect us?
都按您吩咐的办了  这是彩礼
Both done as you asked. And this is the gift.
彩礼
The gift!
送新娘再合适不过了
Perfect for a new bride.
很好  很好
Very good. Very good.
恕我冒昧  我们为何要如此在意
If you don't mind me asking, why are we paying such attention
一名国王护卫的妻子
to the bride of the king's champion?
作为国王的姐姐
As the king's sister,
我理应欢迎所有卡米洛特的新到之客
I should welcome every new arrival into Camelot.
尤其是女人们  我们能赋予彼此力量
Especially the women. We can give each other strength and...
您还好吗
Are you all right?
我没事
I'm fine.
让我帮你吧
Let me help.
我说了我没事
I said I'm fine.
行了
Now,
我的马到底备好了没有
is my horse ready or not?
您昨天就抱痛不已
You were complaining of pains yesterday.
您确定可以骑马吗
Are you sure you're well enough to ride?
你是医生还是仆人
Are you a doctor, or a servant?
我这就去把一切准备停当
I'll ensure everything's ready.
都在这儿了
This is it?
没错
Yes.
我还以为会是一支军队
I thought there'd be an army.
国王的势力才区区如此  当真吗
The king's forces are this few? Really?
我们正在招兵买马
We're recruiting.
那我们为何而战
So what are we fighting for?
此话怎讲
How do you mean?
我们作战的模式  我训练你们的方式
The way we fight, the way I train you all,
都要根据作战目的而定
depends on what we're fighting for.
-我们为自由而战  -谁的自由
- We're fighting for freedom. - Whose?
-全民的  -但不是我的
- Everyone's. - Not mine.
我已是自由之身  可以为所欲为
I'm free already. I can do what I want.
那你为何来此
Well, then why are you here?
他们告诉我你值得效忠
They told me you were worth following.
那我们就为人民而战
Then we're fighting for the people,
为了他们能在乱世中求得自由
for their freedom from chaos.
给他一个机会
Give him a chance.
好吧
All right.
不多说了  让我见识见识你的身手
Forget the talk. Show me how you fight.
也许能为你加一些印象分
Maybe I can make them in your image.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
我不确定你是否准备好了  殿下
I'm not sure you are ready, Your Highness.
行了
All right.
斯巴达  完美的训练场
Sparta. The perfect training ground.
斯巴达 希腊南部的古代城邦
那些混蛋还是有一技之长的
Those bastards were good for something.
好吧  那你就是我们的训练人了
Well, then you are the man to train us.
很高兴你同意了
I'm glad that you agree.
看来你需要一把新剑了
Looks like you need a new sword.
是啊  一把适合国王佩戴的剑
Yes, one suitable for a king.
你知道卡利伯恩吗
Do you know Caliburn?
Caliburn是传中的石中剑
此处为铸剑师的名字
是我见过最棒的刀匠
Best bladesmith I ever met.
他会为你打造一把独一无二的剑
He'll make you something special.
我在哪儿能找到他
Where will I find him?
自他妻子死后  他一直隐居山林中
He's been holed up in the woods since his wife died.
你得多加小心  此人反复无常
You'll need to be careful; He's volatile.
我不介意反复无常
I don't mind volatile.
只要你给我指明方向  我就能找到他
You give me directions, I'll find him.
走之前  我要跟你谈谈
Before I do, a word.
就此打住  不管你对她有什么感情
It stops now. Whatever you feel for her,
立刻一刀两断  你们没有未来
destroy it. It has no future.
-你不能掌控我的未来  -最后通牒
- You don't control my future. - Last warning.
不要让错误的欲望搅乱我们的计划
Don't unsettle our project with misdirected desire.
刻苦训练  我会带着剑回来的
Train hard. I'll return with a sword.
我相信你的新婚之夜一定很称心如意吧
I trust your wedding night was all you hoped for.
我也相信你能理解我不想多做讨论
And I trust you'd understand if I'd prefer to keep it private.
当然
Absolutely.
慎重起见嘛
Discretion in all things.
不过既然你已经成婚了
But now that you are married,
那自然  你会比以往更让人垂涎若渴
of course, you'll be coveted more than ever.
此话怎讲
What do you mean?
对任何男人来说  被禁止的都是最具诱惑力的
Well, the most enticing aspect for any man is the forbidden.
可你必须无视
But you'll just have to forego
除你丈夫外  任何男人的目光
the looks from men other than your husband.
因为关注他们...
For to pay them any heed is really...
实在是一个女人的最不明智之举
Well, it's the worst thing that any woman could do.
我知道那不会有好下场
I've known women's lives come undone that way.
来  我帮你
Here, let me help you.
停
Stop!
我们休息片刻
We should rest a moment.
我要喝点水
I'll take some water.
您病了
You're sick.
我必须去卡米洛特  我要见那女孩
I need to go to Camelot. I have to see this girl.
您玉体欠安  我带您回去
You're not well enough. I'm taking you back.
不行
No!
恕我直言  您的健康是我的首要任务
With respect, your well-being is my priority.
您需要休息
You need to rest.
让我们来照顾您
Let us take care of you.
-你好  -殿下
- Hello. - Your Highness.
-不必如此拘礼  -我理应如此
- You know you don't have to do that. - I think I do.
我们之间现在是怎么了
What happens now? Between us?
什么也没有
Nothing.
我已为人妻
I committed myself.
你祝福了婚戒
You blessed the rings.
我整晚没睡
I didn't sleep the whole night.
我想着他在做什么
I thought about what he was doing.
亚瑟  别说了
Arthur, stop this.
他在行吗  他比我在行吗
Is he good? Is he better than me?
-这话太无礼了  -我想知道
- This isn't appropriate. - I want to know.
这与你无关
It has nothing to do with you!
海滩上的事
On the beach.
是有意义的
It meant something.
不
No.
没有
It didn't.
如果有  你觉得我还会嫁给他吗
If it had, do you think I could've married him?
那我成了什么人了
What sort of person would that have made me?
你把自己给了我
You gave yourself to me.
不管当时那人是谁
Whoever that person was,
她已经消失了
she's gone;
她死了
She's dead.
-那你现在成了什么人  -您护卫的妻子
- Who does that make you? - Your champion's wife.
乐意为您效劳
Honoured to serve you.
愿这能带给你幸福
Well, may it bring you much happiness.
我们到家了  您现在可以休息了
We're home. You can rest now.
不
No.
-把她赶走  -那个修女吗
- Get her out!  - The nun?
她怎么进来的  谁放她进来的
How did she get in? Who let her in?
赶她走  马上
Get her out of here! Now!
-快  -你都干了些什么
- Now.  - What have you done?
赶她走
Get her out!
我不想看到她出现在城堡里
I don't want her within sight of this castle.
我已吩咐卫兵了
I'll have the guards see to it.
不  别让他们去做
No, don't have them see to it!
你亲自去  确保万无一失
You see to it! Make sure it's happened.
当然
Of course.
她是谁
Who is she?
他们得添点柴火了
They need to build up this fire!
几乎没有热气
It's barely giving out any heat!
您很冷
You're cold.
-稍事休息会好的  -发烧而已
- Some rest will help.  - It's just a fever.
当然
Of course.
让我们照顾您吧
Let us look after you.
女侍们会带您回寝宫的
The girls will take you to your chamber.
那女人  不准出现在我视线里
That woman... not within sight.
盾牌是你的最佳盟友
The shield is your greatest ally.
这些看上去还不错
Now, these all look like fine shields.
但还少了点什么
But they're lacking.
你
You.
攻击我
Attack me.
凯
Kay!
在盾牌边缘加装刀片
Line the edge of your shield with a blade.
一把刀或是一把断剑
A knife  or the broken end of a sword.
你们的盾牌将不仅能够防御
Your shield then becomes not just a mode of defence,
还能够作为武器出击
but a weapon in itself.
你没事吧
You all right?
高文  你这个卑鄙小人
You're a dirty fighter, Gawain.
这是格斗  不是做饭
This is combat, not cooking.
我是实战教学
I train by example.
打伤战士就是训练吗
By injuring the warriors you're supposed to be training?
冷静点  别激动
Steady now. Don't get excited...
尤其你现在连剑都没有
Especially now you don't have a sword.
我不需要剑
I don't need a sword.
我需要的是一位德高望重的导师
But what I do need is an honourable instructor...
关于盾牌还有一事
One other thing on shields:
永远在盾牌上绑一把匕首以备不时之需
Always keep a dagger strapped to your shield for emergencies.
匕首是你的一部分
Your dagger is a part of you.
绝不能离身
It should never leave your side.
在上面写字刻字  让它成为你独有的
Inscribe it, carve it, make it your own,
这样不论身处何地  都不会弄混淆
so wherever you are, you'll never mistake it.
格斗还有一些规则  要冷漠无情
Some other rules of combat: Remove your emotions;
镇定自若
Keep calm;
挑衅对手  激发他们的怒气
Attempt to draw your opponent into battle using their anger.
这样他们将极易气馁
That way they're easily frustrated.
拿开你的刀
Take your blade from his throat.
我还是可以取走你和国王的项上人头
I could still take you and the king's head.
-放开他  -只是娱乐一下
- Let him go. - It's just a bit of fun.
让你的娱乐离我弟弟远点
Have your fun away from my brother.
高文  你听到他说的了
You heard what he said, Gawain.
没人可以胁持国王
Nobody threatens the king,
不管是训练还是玩笑
neither in training nor in jest.
-谢谢  -乐意效劳  殿下
- Thank you. - Pleasure, Your Highness.
你的将军和护卫英勇无畏
Your marshal and your champion have got some guts.
你还有一些支持者
And you have some men who'll stand up for you.
很好
Good.
薇薇安  我要用膳
Vivian, I need to eat.
给我食物  要很多  我饿极了
Bring me food. Lots of food. I'm starving.
您可以起来了吗
Should you be up?
您的气色确实好多了
You do look a lot better.
发烧而已
Just a fever.
我们明天去卡米洛特看看这个桂妮维尔
Tomorrow we'll go to Camelot to see this Guinevere.
摩根  抱歉
Morgan, I'm sorry.
她还在外面
She's still outside.
我试着赶走她  但她不肯离开
I tried to move her, but she wouldn't go.
她当然不会离开
Of course she wouldn't.
她到底是什么人
Who is she?
我父王把我放逐到海那边的修道院
My father banished me to a nunnery across the sea.
她教导过我
She taught me.
她不远万里来到这里
Well, she's come a long way.
您不想知道原因吗
You don't want to know why?
她待您很差吗
Did she treat you badly?
我不愿想起那个地方  我已经忘了那里
I don't think about that place now. I left it behind.
-那就不理她  -再来点面包
- So we ignore her. - I need more bread!
怎么了
What's the matter?
您的眼睛...
Your eyes...
只是一滴血
It's just a drop of blood.
不  摩根
No, Morgan,
不只是滴血
it's not.
到处是血
There's blood everywhere.
我该怎么办
What do I do?
你是谁
Who are you?
高文让我来的
Gawain sent me.
我为一把剑而来
I've come for a sword.
剑
A sword?
你的剑吗
For you?
不是
No.
那你可以走了
Then you'd better leave.
不然我把你劈成两半
Before I slit you from arse-hole to cake-hole.
是为了国王的剑
The sword's for the king.
那位新国王
The new king?
你转告这位国王
You tell this king,
如果他想要一把卡利伯恩的剑
if he wants one of Caliburn's swords,
他最好自己来拿
he damn well better get it for himself.
我是铸剑大师
I'm a master bladesmith,
不是什么村野铁匠
not some fucking village forge worker.
我所铸之剑  均为定制
Every sword I make is made to order...
是独一无二的
it's unique.
为他铸剑
To make him a sword,
我得知道他的体重
I'd need to know his weight,
他的挥剑动作
his swing,
他如何战斗   他天性如何
how he fights, what's in his blood.
你想知道的  我都可以告诉你
I can tell you everything you need to know.
-你和他如此亲近吗  -是的
- You're that close to him? - Yes.
你是何人
Who are you?
我叫梅林
My name's Merlin.
新国王派了个巫师来寻求宝剑
The new king sends a sorcerer for a sword.
你有着巫师的时机感
You have a sorcerer's sense of timing.
进来
Come inside.
让你看看我的魔法
I'll show you my magic.
你和其他人等
You and the rest of your household,
都回你们的房间去  关紧房门
go to your rooms. Lock the doors.
为什么
Why?
因为我吩咐你们这样做
Because I told you.
孩子  你看起来很糟
You look terrible, girl.
你是聋了还是蠢  滚
Are you deaf or just stupid? Go!
-如果你需要我...  -她不需要
- If you need me to... - She won't.
我没事
It's all right.
你并非没事  对吗
It's not all right, is it?
肯定很难受
It's not all right at all.
你呕吐过吗
Have you vomited?
-走一走  -什么
- Walk, then. - What?
走路  你知道什么是走路吧
Walk! You know what walking is, don't you?
起来  孩子
Stand up, child!
我办不到
I can't!
四肢逐渐变得无力
The limbs are weakening.
刚才还没有这些印迹
I didn't have them a moment ago.
你的身体正遭受摧残
Your body is under attack.
告诉我实情
Tell me honestly:
自从你离开我们
Since you left us,
你是否进行过召唤
have you performed a summoning?
你是否提了什么要求
Did you ask for anything?
是的
Yes.
我的孩子啊
Oh, my child.
你怎会如此鲁莽
How could you be so reckless?
我到底怎么了
What's happening to me?
很久以前
I told you
我就告诉过你
a long time ago,
你的傲慢终将摧毁你
your arrogance will be your downfall.
我还剩一件事没教你
I have one thing left to teach you.
我不需要你
I don't need you!
我该学的都学完了
I have nothing left to learn!
不
You do.
你还得学会死亡
You must learn to die.
不
No!!
他高大但不强壮
So he's tall but he's not strong.
打斗之时
And when he fights,
他有激情但过于冲动
he's passionate but too impulsive.
是的
Yes.
那他的剑得更重点
He needs to be weighted down more.
-应该没错  -我知道我没错
- You could be right. - I know I'm right.
我自己也曾是名战士
I was a warrior myself.
我以血为荣
I gloried in blood.
我的格言是屠戮沙场
Word of my approach could clear battlefields.
现在
These days,
我不再挥舞武器  而是打造它们
I build the weapons instead of brandishing them.
但某些月夜  风高之时
But some nights, when the wind rages,
我还会闻到阵阵血腥
I still get the smell of blood in my nostrils.
这把剑
This one.
很特别
It's special.
我用仅产于科罗曼德尔海岸的
I made it from an ingot of damascene steel
大马士革钢锻造
found only on the Coromandel shores.
加上精确的含碳量
The precise amount of carbon,
将让剑变得坚不可摧
and the sword becomes almost indestructible.
我从未能控制好各要素间的平衡
I never got the balance right.
直到现在
Until now.
此乃我手艺之巅峰
The zenith of my craft.
万宗归一
Everything in unity.
一把新的王者之剑
A new sword for a new king.
希望如此
Maybe.
那么...
So...
国王的巫师
The king's sorcerer.
你运用你的能力时
When you use your powers,
是什么感觉
how does it feel?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
怎么  你不再用了吗  为什么
What, you don't use them any more? Why not?
在那些激动人心的日子里  你运用之时
When you did, those heady days,
是什么感觉
what was it like?
像是一种别样的情绪
Like an extra emotion.
是吗
Really?
但如果你拥有这样的天赋
But if you have this gift,
为什么不用呢  为什么要克制
why not use it? Why deny yourself?
除非你心存恐惧
Unless you're scared.
不  不
No, no.
比恐惧更甚
It's more than that.
是因为你沉迷其中
Because you enjoy it.
你在干嘛
What're you doing?
你在那多久了
How long have you been there?
-什么  -你看到什么了
- What? - What did you see?
把你的刀从我女儿身上拿开
Take your knife from my daughter.
我以为你独居于此
I thought you lived alone.
我带来了食物
I brought food.
他和我们一起吃吗
Is he going to eat with us?
除非他不再威胁我的小姑娘
Not if he keeps threatening my little girl.
你知道他是谁吗
You know who this is?
著名巫师  梅林
The famous sorcerer, Merlin.
她是艾克斯卡利伯
Excalibur.
艾克斯卡利伯  他是梅林
Excalibur, Merlin.
我会给你们都弄点吃的
I'll make enough for both of you.
她很美
She's beautiful.
为了生她  她母亲死于难产
Her mother died giving birth to her.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
你有家室吗
You have family?
现在没了
Not any more.
只有你的国王了
Just your king.
一起吃晚饭吧
Eat with us.
休整一宿
Then we rest.
明日一早
And in the morning,
国王的宝剑便会铸好了
you will have your sword for your king.
战士需要休息
A warrior needs his sleep.
国王更是如此
A king even more so.
今晚无法入睡了
Can't manage it tonight.
我有事请教
But I do have a question for you.
但说无妨
All right.
关于兵法
About strategy.
我可不是将领  只是区区一个士兵
I'm not a commander; I'm a soldier.
我曾读兵书
I've read about many battles,
习兵法
about the great strategists.
但仍有一事不甚明了
But what I don't understand is this:
如何知道何时该放弃
How do I know when it's time to give up?
何时该承认强者已然胜出
When do I acknowledge the better man's victory?
士兵从来不必操心这等事
See, the warrior would never do that.
他只需为信仰鞠躬尽瘁  死而后已
He'd fight to the death for something he believed in.
不过  在最糟之时
Of course, at the lowest moment,
倒是有一次机会
you have one opportunity.
此话怎讲
And what's that?
失去所有之时
When you have nothing to lose,
便是破釜沉舟之刻
that's the time to risk everything.
不要挣扎
Try not to struggle.
我不会死
I will not die.
帮我度过这一劫
Get me through this!
很好  就这样想
Good. You hold onto that.
别忘了
And remember,
你来这里是有所图的
you came back here for a reason.
王位
The crown.
王位对你意味几何
How much does it mean to you?
-一...  -我听不见  说出来
- Ev... - I can't hear you! Talk!
一切
Everything.
什么
What?
一切
Everything!
那就斗下去
Then fight!
你罪有应得
You deserved what you got.
父王
Father.
可怜的弱者
Weak little wretch!
宣誓效忠于本王
Swear your fealty!
狡猾的贱货
Clever bitch!
我没有你这个女儿
I no longer have a daughter.
阴险的贱货  可怜的弱者
Clever bitch! Weak little wretch!
你会被私生子打得落花流水
Beaten by a bastard.
可怜的弱者  被私生子打得落花流水
Weak little wretch! Beaten by a bastard.
我不会被打败
I'm not beaten!
你罪有应得  你会一无所有
You deserve what you got... nothing!
摩根  摩根
Morgan! Morgan!
摩根  听着
Morgan, listen!
你有多渴望得到王位
How much do you want the crown?
有多渴望活下去
How much do you want to live?
一把新的王者之剑
A new sword for a new king.
我以血为荣
I gloried in blood.
大功告成
It's done.
此乃出自我手的至尊之剑
The best I've ever made.
永不磨损  无坚可摧
Almost indestructible.
能否一试
Can I?
我要亲自呈给国王
I'll give it to the king myself.
你想拿我的成果邀功请赏
You want the credit for my work.
不  但我不想让你靠近国王
No. But I don't need you near my king.
难道我能为他铸此宝剑
I'm good enough to make him a weapon,
却不配亲自觐见
but not to stand in his presence?
你身上仍有杀气
You still have the smell of blood in your nostrils.
而你仍会施巫术
And you still have sorcery within you.
宝剑你休想拿走
The sword stays with me.
你只要铸好宝剑即可
You shaped it for the king.
我要将它呈给国王
And I'm taking it to him.
凭你
You?
把剑交给我
Give me the sword.
自己来取
Take it.
来啊  以为我不会还手吗
Come on. You think I won't fight back?
你若还有家人  我会送他们去和你团聚
And if you still had a family, they'd be next!
不准提他们
Don't speak of them!
你做了什么
What've you done?
-只是意外  -不  你杀了他
- There was an accident. - No, you killed him!
不  不  不  不...
No, no, no, no...
-你就为这个杀了他  -把剑给我
- You killed him for this? - Give me the sword.
把剑给我
Give me the sword.
你永远别想得到这把剑
You'll never have this sword!
艾克斯卡利伯  别跑  拜托
Excalibur, wait! Please!
只是意外
It was an accident!
艾克斯卡利伯  停下来
Excalibur, stop!
别过来
Stay away from me!
把剑给我
Give me the sword.
-求你把剑给我  -不
- Please, give it to me. - No!
这把剑只应葬身湖底
The only place for it is the bottom of this lake!
宝剑非我王莫属
The king must have his sword...
别过来
Stay away from me!
别追我
Leave me alone!
走开
Go away!
别动
Stay where you are.
艾克斯卡利伯  别动
Excalibur, don't move!
艾克斯卡利伯
Excalibur!
不
No!
艾克斯卡利伯
Excalibur!
坚持住  坚持住
Stay with me! Stay with me!
坚持住
Stay with me!
不
No!
坚持住
Stay with me!
对不起
I'm sorry.
可怜的孩子
You poor child.
摩根
Morgan!
你是谁
Who are you?
呼吸
Breathe!
呼吸  慢点  慢点
Breathe! Slowly! Slowly!
我没死
I lived.
慢慢来
Go slowly.
你错了  你说我会死
You were wrong; You said I'd die.
你重生了
You were reborn.
因为我命硬
Because I'm strong.
摩根
Morgan.
别碰我  怎么回事
Stay away from me! Oh, what's this?
上帝啊
Dear God.
怎么了
What?
不...
No...
不  不要是她
No! No, not her!
谁都可以  不要是她  不
No, anyone but her! No!
-冷静 冷静  冷静  -不
- Stop! Stop! Stop! - No!
不  不  我无法接受
No, no! I can't bear it!
别反抗  要去适应
Don't fight it. Settle.
适应
Settle.
感受她的内心
Inside her.
呼吸
Breathe.
呼吸  呼吸  呼吸
Breathe. Breathe. Breathe.
很好
Good.
怎么  怎么了
What? What is it?
我能感觉到她
I can feel her.
我能感其所感
I can feel what she's feeling.
她很痛苦
She's feeling pain.
会有其他人适合你的
There'll be another one for you.
我是说桂妮维尔
Guinevere.
我看到你看她的眼神了
I saw the way you looked at her.
你会找到其他人选的
You'll find another.
这是你作为母亲的建议吗
Is that your motherly advice?
我是想保护你
I'm trying to protect you.
到别处找找看吧
Look somewhere else.
你也是这么跟我父亲说的吗
Is that what you told my father?
你知道损失有多惨重吗
Do you have you any idea how much was destroyed?
你知道因为没人阻止他  有多少人丧命吗
How many people died because he wouldn't be denied?
我不会让悲剧重演的
I will not let that happen again.
你迟到了  殿下
You're late... Your Highness.
想知道我的价值观是吧
You want to know my values.
听好了  杀戮之时  我们要心怀慈悲
Well, here they are: when we have to kill, we do it with mercy.
要知道我们任重而道远
We do it knowing we have a higher course.
我们要为和平而战
We fight for peace.
自相矛盾
Contradiction in terms.
不  要练习作战  但更要实践和平
No. Train for battle; Practice peace.
战斗只是我们实现其他目标的手段  荣誉
Combat is the means by which we achieve other things: honour,
保卫  正义等  我们并非为了战斗而战斗
protection, justice. It is not an end in itself.
说完了吗
Is that it?
没有
No.
跟我打
Fight me.
放倒我
Take me down.
没事的
It's fine.
要明白对方比你强
Understand when you've been beaten by a better man.
但永远不要放弃
But never give in!
永远  不放弃
Never, give in.
即使你觉得自己已一无所有
Even if it feels like you've lost everything.
如果为了目的而必须不择手段
And if you have to fight dirty to protect your cause...
那就不择手段吧
Then so be it.
这才像话
Now this,
这才是我能与之共事的国王
this is a king I can do business with.
我知道你在做什么  你得停手
I know what you're doing and you have to stop.
我不明白你的意思
I don't know what you mean.
我得对里昂提斯负责
I have a duty to Leontes.
你得对你的人民负责
You have a duty to your people.
我们要各尽其职  之前的事只是过眼云烟
We follow our duties and nothing we did before matters.
告诉我你得偿所愿了  那我就停手
Tell me you have what you want, and I'll stop.
我看到你的所作所为了
I saw what you did.
我不是一场你能赢得的打斗
I'm not a fight you can win.
你看着我的眼睛说出来  我就停手
I'll stop if you look at me in the eye and say it.
我很幸福
I'm happy.
我得偿所愿了
I have what I want.
那就到此为止了
Then it's finished.
-国王万岁  -我得为此干一杯
- Long live the king! - I'll drink to that.
蠢货
Fools.
你说什么
What did you say?
我说你娘生你的时候肯定受了刺激
I said your mother must've wept the day she bore you...
你俩都是
Both of you.
我猜你们是兄弟吧  真够丑的
I assume you're brothers... you're ugly enough.
这也叫打人
Call that a punch?
你为何前来
Why did you come?
修道院被烧毁了
The nunnery burned.
我们受到了袭击
We were attacked.
我是唯一的幸存者
I was the only survivor.
我独自一人  这令我恐惧
I'm alone; It frightens me.
我是被指引到这里的
I was drawn here
恰恰在你最需要我的时候
just when you needed me.
-我不需要你  -你离开我们来寻求王位
- I don't need you. - You left us to get the crown.
至今仍未得手
You don't have it yet.
薇薇安
Vivian.
给这女人收拾一间客房
Make up a bed for this woman.
离我的寝宫越远越好
As far away from my chamber as you can find.
遵命
Of course.
你怎么了
What happened to you?
无所谓
Doesn't matter.
当然有所谓
Of course it does.
你的剑
Your sword.
天啊
Oh, my God.
简直非同凡响
It's extraordinary.
真美啊
It's a thing of beauty.
谢谢
Thank you.
得给它起个名字
It needs a name.
已经有名字了
It already has a name.
是我让你去找的那个卡利伯恩造的吗
Is it from Caliburn, the man I sent you to see?
不  我到的时候他已经去世了
No. When I got there, he was dead.
我又骑马前行了一段路
I rode many miles.
来到了一座湖边
Until I came to a lake.
四周都是迷雾
And everywhere there was a mist.
我只好停了下来
I had to stop.
然后
And when I did...
当我走出迷雾
Out of the mist...
一个女人呼唤着我的名字
A woman called to me...
宛如海妖
Like a Siren.
Siren是希腊神话中一种半人半鸟的海妖
常用歌声使得过往水手倾听失神  导致航船触礁沉没
她从湖里
From within the lake...
伸出了手臂
She stretched out her arm...
这把剑
This sword,
就握在她手中
clutching it.
我接过了剑
I took the sword...
向她致谢
And thanked her.
她莞尔一笑
She smiled...
退回了湖中
And slipped back into the water.
同时
And as she did...
她说
She said,
"此乃亚瑟王之剑"
"This is the sword of King Arthur."
"名曰"
"This..."
"王者之剑"
"Is Excalibur".
Excalibur -- 王者之剑或圣剑
音译即艾克斯克利伯   前段在湖中溺死的女孩
此处梅林虚构的故事其实是更为普及的传说版本
即圣剑是由湖中女妖从湖中托出的
特此注释  供观众参考